How long does it take you to fall asleep?
你需要多长时间才能入睡？
Are you out like a light as soon as your head hits the pillow, or does it take you more than a little time to doze off?
你的头一碰到枕头就立刻入睡（out like a light），还是需要相当长的时间才能睡着？
If the average night’s sleep is eight hours, or a third of a day, then it means we spend around one third of our lives in this dormant state.
如果平均每晚睡眠8小时，也就是一天的三分之一，那么这意味着我们一生中大约有三分之一的时间处于这种休眠的（dormant）状态。
Science already has reams of data on the brain’s activity during sleep itself.
科学领域已经有了大量的（reams of）关于睡眠期间大脑活动的数据。
Now, an international group of researchers at the University of Cambridge are researching that dopey state we all go through between wide awake and fast asleep.
现在，剑桥大学的一个国际研究团队正在研究我们都会经历的从完全清醒到熟睡之间那种昏昏欲睡的（dopey）状态。
This transitional period usually lasts between five and 20 minutes, says Sridhar Rajan Jagannathan, one of Cambridge’s Gates Scholars.
剑桥大学盖茨学者斯里达尔・拉詹・贾甘纳坦（Sridhar Rajan Jagannathan）说，这个过渡阶段通常持续5到20分钟。
However, people exhibit a variety of behaviour within this time.
然而，人们在这段时间内会表现出各种各样的行为。
For some, going to the land of nod is a smooth, quick journey, while others have more difficulty.
对有些人来说，进入梦乡（the land of nod）是一个顺畅、快速的过程，而另一些人则更困难。
They “begin to get drowsy” and then snap out of it “back to alertness” he says.
他说，他们“开始变得昏昏欲睡（drowsy）”，然后又突然清醒过来“恢复警觉”。
The aim of the research is to find out how this pre-sleep phase, when the eyes glaze, the attention wanders and the mind is lulled, could be linked to accidents and dangerous mistakes.
这项研究的目的是弄清楚，当眼睛变得呆滞（glaze）、注意力分散、大脑平静下来（lulled）时，这个睡前阶段与意外事故和危险失误之间可能存在怎样的联系。
This could happen during the day while at work.
这种情况可能在白天工作时发生。
“If you’re doing some boring task, you might be drowsy in this period.
贾甘纳坦先生说：“如果你在做一些无聊的任务，在这个阶段你可能会昏昏欲睡。
Small drift-offs can cause big problems,” says Mr Jangannathan.
短暂的瞌睡（drift-offs）可能会导致大问题。”
This is not just connected to safety concerns with driving, for example, but any task where concentration and decision making are important.
这不仅仅与例如安全驾驶问题有关，还与任何需要集中注意力和做出决策的任务有关。
There are positive sides to this hypnagogic period too.
这个半梦半醒的（hypnagogic）阶段也有积极的一面。
Some experts think there is a connection to creativity and imagination.
一些专家认为它与创造力和想象力有关。
This is caused by a reduction in your inhibitions, which makes you more creative.
这是由于抑制作用的减弱，这使你更具创造力。
You have more freedom to express yourself, and you’re more willing to make mistakes.
你有更多自由来表达自己，也更愿意犯错。
It certainly seems to support the old adage of sleeping on it to solve a problem.
这似乎确实支持了“把问题留到第二天再解决（sleeping on it）”这句古老的谚语。
Ultimately, there are hopes that research into brain activity during falling asleep and waking might help stroke victims who are trying to regain lost physical functions.
最终，人们希望对入睡和醒来时大脑活动的研究可能会帮助中风患者恢复失去的身体功能。
That could well be a pipe dream.
这很可能只是一个空想（pipe dream）。
There are also research efforts underway to find ways to warn of the onset of sleep, identifying changes in eye movements or brain activity.
目前也正在进行研究，试图找到方法来预警睡眠的开始，识别眼球运动或大脑活动的变化。
These could have practical applications for tired people operating heavy machinery and may help ensure that when it comes to accidents, we’re not caught napping.
这些研究对于操作重型机械的疲劳人群可能有实际应用，并且可能有助于确保在事故发生时，我们不会措手不及（caught napping）。